What do you mean?
You didn't hear?
Nope!
Wash It
All Away
Episode 10    A Top-Class Challenge!
All right, all right.
Good!
Boy, what a disaster.
Just like that.
Yeah. Good, good.
Yes, I'm sorry.
It even broke the patio roof.
Well, I know it's not actually your fault.
That said, I'm still gonna have to
add the repair cost to your rent.
Yeah...
Just kidding.
Here you go. Do your thing.
Oh, of course! I'll take care of this.
I know plenty of other shops that are
just as cheap and fast as yours, though.
Yeah...
Just kidding. Kidding.
Aji-san is always like this.
Kinme Cleaning
But it is very kind of her to let me
rent this shop for such low rent.
I'm sorry, Kinme-san! I really need
your help with something.
Oh, Yagara-san. What happened?
Shouldn't you be at work?
Huh?
Did something happen to your shop?
Yes, actually.
During the big storm the other day,
lightning struck a tree in the back.
Huh? Are you serious? That's terrible!
That storm sure was something, though.
Power went out at my run-down apartment,
so nobody could use the shared bath.
Yes, that would be inconvenient.
Uh, so what did you
want to ask me, Yagara-san?
Oh, right. Would you look at this?
I-Isn't that...
Yup. Sumi ink. I stupidly got some on me.
I tried to wipe it off with a tissue,
but that didn't help at all.
Oh! There's some on your left sleeve too.
It must have brushed against the skirt.
Huh? No way!
Give me a break!
Things just aren't going my way today.
And September's only just started.
How...
Hmm?
How long has it been since it got stained?
Hmm, let's see. It was this morning,
so about three hours.
Huh? Then we have to deal with it
right this instant!
Huh?
Treating sumi ink stains
is a race against time!
Speaking from personal experience,
they're even worse than squid ink.
Well, squid ink stains are also difficult,
but of all the kinds of stains out there,
sumi ink is a top-class challenge!
Sumi Ink
Kinme
Wakana
Challenge!
There are several different
kinds of stains.
Resin
Water-soluble
Dye
Bleach
Ooh, time for another knowledge drop!
Oil-soluble
We can separate them
into a few main categories.
Protein
Insoluble
Water-soluble
Alcohol
Sauce
Soy Sauce
Water-soluble stains dissolve in water...
Oil-soluble
Vegetable Oil
Sesame
Oil
while oil-soluble stains dissolve in oil.
Those are two main types.
But there are also stains that
don't dissolve easily in water or oil.
Those are called "insoluble," and the
best-known example of that is sumi ink.
Huh.
It is extremely difficult to clean
stains like these at home.
Wow, really?
And ink stains get harder to remove
the longer they sit untreated.
So before I get started,
I feel I must warn you
that I may not be able
to remove the ink completely.
There is a risk
a faint stain might remain.
If that happens, I will return the clothes
without charging you for the cleaning.
What would you like to do?
What are you talking about?
Of course I want you to clean them!
H-Huh? Hey!
Hmm? What's wrong?
Uh... don't take them off here!
Th-There are people around!
Come on. It's fine! I even brought
a change of clothes with me.
You've got to start cleaning
this instant, right?
Whoa! Y-Yagara-san, stop it!
Go inside and change in the back!
Aww, are you sure?
Well, I will take care of them.
Okay. Do your best, Kinme-san.
Right.
You can count on Kinme.
Um, excuse me.
Yes?
We've finished removing the fallen tree.
Thank you very much. I appreciate it.
You bet.
Looks like two or three tries
isn't going to do it.
Oh, maybe I'll give that a shot.
Sumi ink is very resistant
to chemical treatments.
If I can get another material
to absorb some of the ink
and do that over and over...
then bit by bit...
Goodbye, Sensei!
Yeah, goodbye! Take care, okay?
I feel bad! I didn't mean to
make you come all the way here.
Well, you have your hands full
with the new term.
I appreciate it.
It's no trouble.
Wow! It's all gone!
Amazing! Thank you!
Um...
I'm terribly sorry!
Huh?
There's still a faint stain left
on part of the skirt.
It was beyond my abilities as a cleaner.
Huh? Where?
Oh, right here?
I can barely even see it!
It's totally okay.
Don't worry about it.
So what do I owe you?
I cannot accept payment.
Huh?
I was unable to do my job
and remove it completely.
As such, I cannot accept payment.
What are you talking about?
I'm totally satisfied with your work.
I can't.
But it's 99 percent gone!
She sure can be stubborn.
Then how's this? I'll bring you another
tasty gift instead. Whaddya say?
Thank you very much.
Sensei!
Praying Mantis
Year Three, Class One
Katakuchi Nairo
I was able to write "praying mantis"!
Please take a look!
Oh, it's Kinme-oneesan! Hello!
Huh? What? Yagara-san,
are you and Nairo-chan...
She is my homeroom teacher.
She's a student in my class.
Huh?!
Katakuchi-san, how many of these have you
brought me since class this morning?
This is the fifth one!
The fifth one already?
That's right.
Rather impressive, kiddo!
Does that mean the sumi ink
on your clothes was from...
What? No, I spilled it on myself.
Oh.
Wash It All Away
Thank you so much, Hatsuayu-san!
I really appreciate you
coming over to pick me up.
Not at all. It's the least I can do.
I'm the one who invited you
to lunch, after all.
I'm so happy I get to see your place
and enjoy your home cooking!
Well, you've already done so much for me.
E-Especially for my social skills.
Th-The rest of the family is
at a memorial service today,
so I'm the only one here.
You decided not to go with them?
Uh, yes. We need to have
at least one person at home.
Uh... right. You see, there's something
I forgot to ask you about.
Yes?
M-My family has, um...
S-Stop that right now.
U-Um...
E-Er...
Y-You don't have to worry.
Konatsu and Dai are very gentle.
K-Kinme-san, are you
comfortable around large dogs?
Uh, sure.
But I sweat a lot,
so I wonder if they smell me.
K-Kinme-san, what time did you
have to be back at work?
Oh. Half past two,
so there's still plenty of time.
I-It'll be ready soon,
so please wait just a little longer.
O-Okay.
Whoa! No! Not... Not there!
Huh? Kinme-san, what's the matter?
Nothing. I'm fine.
Big dogs sure are cute.
But...
B-Because it's my job, I can't help
but notice the dirt and dog hair
on this sofa cover and rug.
Thank you for waiting.
Please come this way.
Oh, lovely!
I don't think I've ever had
authentic paella before!
Well, it's actually a quickie recipe
that uses a rice cooker.
I don't think you can call it authentic.
You know, I was actually getting a little
worried that you weren't eating properly.
Huh?
Well, remember Hatsushima?
It's so delicious!
It's been so long since
I've had a proper meal!
What does Hatsuayu-san usually eat anyway?
Oh. I'm sorry to make you worry.
Actually, cooking has always been
one thing that I really enjoy.
But I've been so busy recently,
I haven't been able to cook much.
That's good to know.
Well, if you don't mind, I'll dig in.
Delicious!
Oh my. We're being watched.
The carpaccio is delicious too!
The fish is sea bass I bought down
at the seafood market.
Oh? I do a lot of shopping
at the seafood market too!
Huh? I wonder if we've crossed
paths there before!
I wanted to thank you
for coming today and, well,
actually, for every day
I see you at the public bath.
Hmm?
Thanks to your help,
my social skills are getting better,
so I'm having less trouble at work.
I think I'm learning to enjoy
my job a lot more now.
A-Actually, I don't think I've ever...
invited a stranger over
to my place before.
This might be the first time.
I always tended to be withdrawn
at school, and kind of a homebody,
so I'm a little surprised at myself
for being able to pull this off.
I think that since meeting you,
I've started to change a little.
Oh, gosh. What am I rambling about anyway?
Uka-san.
You're wrong about one thing.
We aren't strangers anymore.
We are definitely friends.
Thank you for the meal!
It really was a delicious lunch.
Oh, not at all.
Well, I guess I'll drive you back.
Huh? Where did the dogs go?
Huh?
Th-The sliding glass door...
I must have totally forgotten to latch it!
Hey, you two!
S-Stop playing with the water!
Oh, now you're both such a mess!
Konatsu, Dai, you really have to behave!
Hey! Don't put your paw on my skirt!
Let me give you a hand.
Well, what can you do?
Bye! See you next time!
I'm sorry it got so late.
No, no, it's fine.
We haven't had a new guest
over in a long time,
so the dogs got a little excited.
They even got your blouse dirty.
You have to go back to work now, too.
It's okay. I can change
into something else.
They took me by surprise at first,
but the dogs sure were adorable!
So, about the sofa cover,
is this really okay with you?
Are you sure you really
don't want me to pay?
You treated me to a really
wonderful time today.
Think of it as my way of saying thanks.
Then thank you very much.
Okay, then. Thank you for this.
Sure.
I-I guess I'll see you at the bath.
Of course! Thank you again for lunch.
Oh, Aji-san! Good afternoon!
Hmph.
I didn't realize you were here.
I came to check out the backyard.
The repair men sure are dragging
their feet. What are they up to anyway?
I wish they'd shake
a leg and get it fixed.
I'm sure they're busy around town with
all the damage caused by the storm.
Hmph.
The heck is that?
Oh. That's a paw print from a dog.
My! So you spent your lunch break
playing with dogs?
I bet if I leave my laundry
for you to wash,
everything will come back
with a paw stamp on it.
Same old, same old.
Yeah...
I'm just kidding.
Well, I saw what I needed to, so I'm off.
She tries not to show it,
but she was so worried about me
that she came to check the shop.
It's already past two thirty now.
Do you mind?
Oh! Of course!
I-I need to go change,
so please give me a minute.
Translation:
Editing and Typesetting:
Michael Arnold
Ashley Barboza
Quality Control:
Translation Check:
Riley Dalton
Sriram Gurunathan
Huh?
Wakana-san i-isn't coming over today.
Episode 11 To Help This Little Guy Out
Next time, "To Help This Little Guy Out."